Bertha C. Reynolds Papers, 1907-1994
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- Series II. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES 1919-1975
  - National Maritime Union
    - Staff meetings: minutes, 1944-45 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Staff policies and procedures: position papers, notes, 1944-46, undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Clippings and other printed materials, 1943-47, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Pamphlets, 1942-45, undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - United Seamen's Service: correspondence, 1947-52, undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - William Alanson White Institute
    - Seminar: bulletin, correspondence, 1949, 1954, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Speeches, Institutes, Seminars
    - First International Conference on Mental Hygiene: correspondence, abstract, printed material, 1929-30 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - First International Conference on Mental Hygiene: proceedings, program, 1930,1932 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Invitations to speak: correspondence, 1947-75 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - Speaking dates and institutes: lists made by Bertha C. Reynolds, 1933-57 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Consultant in Staff Development: brochure, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Association of Massachusetts State Hospital Social Workers, debate: typescript -, 1919 Jul 10 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Institute on Supervision, Cleveland:typed notes, 1932 Oct 25-26 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Institute, St. Louis: typed notes, 1933 Apr 8-9 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - "The Relationship Between Psychiatry and Psychiatric Social Work," American Association of Psychiatric Social, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Workers, Kansas City: text "Critic's Response," American, 1935 Feb 22 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Orthopsychiatric Association: text "Loyalties," the Supervisors Association,of the Emergency Relief Bureau, New York: notes and correspondence, 1935 Dec (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Child Welfare Training Supervisors' Institute, Cleveland: transcribed notes, 1936 Feb l8-19 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - "Changing Attitudes in Case Work,"Detroit Regional Conference of Social Work: text, 1936 Apr 17-18 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - "Mental Hygiene in Social Work,"Frankwood E. Williams memorial meeting, New York: text, 1936 Nov 15 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - "Inter-relations Between Group Work and Case Work, and What a Course in Case Work can give to Group Workers-in-Training That Will Meet Their Needs in Their Own Field," seminar, Temple University, Philadelphia: outline, reports of planning committee meetings, notes, 1936 Nov-1937 Jan (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - "Worker-Client Relationships, or Responsibility in Social Case Work," Institute, New England Inter-City Conference of Family Welfare Societies, Cambridge: report of sessions, 1937 Feb 26-27 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Radio talk, Community Forum, St. Louis: text, 1939 Jan 21 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - In-Service Training Course, Seminar on Interviewing, Domestic Relations Court, New York: reports of sessions, 1939 Nov-Mar (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Institute, State Supervisory Staff, Dept. of Public Welfare, Richmond: letter describing one session, 1940 Nov-Jan (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Staff Discussion Group, Medical Social Service Department, Bellevue Hospital, New York: reports of sessions, 1940 Feb-Apr (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - "Social Breakdown," Psychiatric Social Workers' Round Table, Providence: notes, 1940 Feb 7 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - "Supervision of Supervisors," Summer Institute, Michigan State College, East Lansing: notes, 1940 Jul 15-19 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Discussion of paper of Almena Dawley, American Orthopsychiatric Association: text, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - "Diagnostic Case Recording," Institute,Council of Social Agencies, Dayton: summary, 1941 Jan 23-24 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - "Conversation Overheard This Morning," Psychiatric Supervisors' Seminar, New York School of Social Work: notes, 1941 Mar 19 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - "Social Work Trying to Practice Democracy," Institute, AASW Chapter, Columbus: text, 1941 Apr 24 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - "Case Work-Group Work: Relationships and Cooperative Services," seminar: notes, 1941 May 19 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Institute on Supervision, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge: outline, 1941 Jul 7-11 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - "Social Work in the National Emergency," Conference on Social Work in the National Emergency, Social Service Administration Club, University of Chicago: summary, 1941 Aug 15-16 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - "Personal Service to Seamen," National Conference of Social Work, Cleveland: text, 1944 May (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - "Health Security in Post War America," Second Wartime Conference on Labor Health Security, New York: text, 1944 Dec 8 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - "Recognition of the Right to Assistance and its Effect on Social Work in a Public Assistance Agency," National Conference of Social Work, Buffalo: text, correspondence, 1946 May 23 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - "Social Psychiatry and Personal Service in a Social Agency-Trade Union Setting," American Orthopsychiatric Association: text, discussion, 1947 Feb (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - "Our Future in Social Work ... With What Allies?" Local 19 and National Social Service Division, UOPWA: transcript, 1948 Feb 14 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - "Are Private Agencies Meeting Their Responsibilities?" National Conference of Social Work: announcement, 1948 Apr (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - "Preparation of Social Workers for Meeting the Emotional Needs of People," South East Regional Conference on Student Education, Nashville School of Social Work, Nashville: text, 1948 Jun 9 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - "Supervision as a Means of Professional Growth," Institute on Social Welfare University of California, Berkeley: summary, 1948 Jul 23-24 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - "Responsibility of Social Work to the People It Serves," National Conference of Social Work, Cleveland: announcement, 1949 Jun (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Consultations, Menninger Foundation: correspondence, schedule, 1950 Jan 30-Feb 1 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - "Differences within Labor and their Effect on the Social Work Field: From the Point of View of the Profession," National Conference of Social Work, Atlantic City: text, announcement, correspondence, 1950 Apr (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - "The Child's Needs in the Family," panel leader, National Bread and Butter Conference on Child Welfare, Chicago: proceedings, program, 1950 Apr 15-16 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - "Some Contributions and Challenges of Today," Tennessee State Conference of Social Work: text, 1950 May 5 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - "Civil Liberties and Peace," discussion, New England Conference of Minute Women for Peace: notes, 1950 Jun 24 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - "Problems Facing the Social Worker Today," Philadelphia Chapter, American Association of Group Workers: correspondence, program, 1951 Apr 7 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - "Social Work and Social Living," discussion, Los Angeles: announcement, 1951 May 10 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - "Casework in a Time of Stress" and "Social Workers' Professional Responsibilities," pre-conference seminars, Oregon State Conference of Social Work, Portland: program, 1951 May 23-24 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - "Social Work Faces World Conflict," Social Service Volunteers for Peace, New York: text, correspondence, broadside, 1952 Jan 30 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - "Social Work and Social Living," American Association of Group Workers, Detroit: notes, program. 1952 Apr 26 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - "We Are Responsible," American Association of Social Workers, Connecticut State Conference of Social Work, Hartford: text (part), program, 1952 Nov 13 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Seminar on Social Work and Seminar on Social Group Work, courses given at Jefferson School of Social Science, New York: outlines, 1953 Mar-May (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - "Fear in our Culture," Cleveland Council of Arts, Sciences and Professions, National Conference of Social Work, Cleveland: text, broadside. 1953 Jun 4 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - "From Korean Truce to World Peace," National Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, New York: broadside, outline, 1953 Sep 27 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - "From Mass to Individual; From Isolation to a Social Community," Family Service of Oakland County, Birmingham, Michigan: text, correspondence, 1954 Jan 26 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - "McCarthyism vs. Social Work," National Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions, New York: broadside, text (1954 May 5), 1954 May 12 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - "From Mass to Individual; From Isolation, toward a Social Community," Jefferson School, New York: text, 1956 Mar 8 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Comment on "Social Work: A Profession Chasing its Tail," California Conference on Health, Welfare and Recreation, San Jose: clippings, text, correspondence, 1957 May (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - "Is Social Work a Profession Chasing its Tail? (Social Work in the Light of its History)," Family Service Staff, Los Angeles: notes, 1957 Jun 5 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - "Social Work and the World's Dilemma: What to Do with the Throwaways," institute, Mt. Zion Hospital, San Francisco: outline, 1957 Apr 25-26 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Workshop on Staff Supervision, National Association of Social Workers, Los Angeles: schedule and bibliography, 1957 Jun 11 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - "Mental Health Concepts in the Practice and Teaching of Social Work," the Ruth Kotinsky Memorial Lectures, New York: text, correspondence, announcement, 1961 Apr 21 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - "The Social Casework of an Uncharted Journey," New York Chapter, Alumnae Association, Smith College School for Social Work, New York (also given to supervisors of Simmons College of Social Work, 1964 Apr 8): text, 1963 Oct 24 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - "Human Rights," Blue Hill Chapter, Women's International League for Peace and Freedom: text, 1963 Dec 9 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - "Social Work and the Life of its Time," Maryland Chapter, National Association of Social Workers, Baltimore: text, 1965 Jan 21 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - "What Can Science Do for Warmth of Understanding," Social Service, Johns Hopkins Hospital, Baltimore: text, 1965 Jan 21 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - "Individual Freedom in an Advanced Industrial Society," Brandeis University, Waltham: text, 1965 Apr 29 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - "Learning and Teaching in the Practice of Social Work," Conference of Supervisors and Teachers, Boston University of Social Work: text, 1965 May 14 (Box 5, Folder 80)
- Series III. WRITINGS 1918-1975
  - Correspondence About Publications
    - An Uncharted Journey
      - Publication Committee, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 81)
      - Publication Committee, 1960 Jan-Sep (Box 6, Folder 82)
      - Publication Committee, 1960 Oct-Nov (Box 6, Folder 83)
      - Publication Committee, 1961-1962 Jun (Box 6, Folder 84)
      - Publication Committee, 1962 Jul-1963 (Box 6, Folder 85)
      - Book contract and correspondence, 1962 Jul (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - "Advance or Retreat", 1948 (Box 6, Folder 87)
    - "The American Family and Socialism", 1956-57 (Box 6, Folder 88)
    - "Focus on Peace", 1952 (Box 6, Folder 89)
    - Learning and Teaching in the Practice of Social Work, 1942-43, 1959-77 (Box 6, Folder 90)
    - "The Press Lies about Relief", 1947 (Box 6, Folder 91)
    - "Re-Thinking Social Case Work", 1948 (Box 6, Folder 92)
    - Social Work and Social Living, 1948-51 (Box 6, Folder 93)
    - Social Work and Social Living, National Association of Social Workers Classics Series, 1974-76 (Box 6, Folder 94)
    - Social Work Today (England), 1970, undated (Box 6, Folder 95)
    - Correspondence about other articles and book reviews, 1941-73 (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Published Works, [see also Books and pamphlets on shelf]
    - Lists of writings, ca. 1968, undated (Box 6, Folder 97)
    - Articles, 1931-37 (Box 6, Folder 98)
    - Articles, 1938-64 (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - Article, "Is Homemaking a Helping Profession?": typescript, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - Book reviews by Reynolds, 1933-59 (Box 7, Folder 101)
    - Reviews of Reynolds's books, 1935-75 (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - Essays in books, 1948, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 103)
    - Pamphlets and reprints, 1919-48 (Box 7, Folder 104)
    - Published letters, 1955, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - Reports, Danvers State Hospital, 1918, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 106)
    - Books, 1934-73
      - Between Client and Community: A Study in Responsibility: Social Case Work (New York: Oriole Editions, Inc., 1973), first published in Smith College Studies in Social Work 5 (1934): 1-128 (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - ________Silver Spring, Md.: NASW Classics Series, National Association of Social Workers, Inc., 1982 ) (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - Learning and Teaching in the Practice of Social Work (New York: Farrar & Rinehart, Inc., 1942 ) (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - ________(New York: Rinehart & Co., Inc., 1942; 5th printing Mar. 1953 ) (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - ________(New York: Russell & Russell, Inc., 1965 ) (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - ________(Silver Spring, Md.: NASW Classics Series, National Association of Social Workers, Inc., 1985 ) (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - Social Work and Social Living: Explorations in Philosophy and Practice (New York: Citadel Press, 1951 ) (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - ________(Washington, D.C.: NASW Classics Series, National Association of Social Workers, Inc. 1975 ) (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - An Uncharted Journey: Fifty Years of Growth in Social Work (New York: The Citadel Press, 1963 ) (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - ________(New York: The Citadel Press, 1963 ) (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - ________(Hebron, Conn.: Practitioners Press, 1985 ) (Box 8, Folder 107)
      - An Uncharted Journey: typescript, 1963? (Box 9, Folder 108)
      - Social Work and Social Living: typescript, undated (Box 10, Folder 109)
    - Other Published Works
      - Manuscripts and typescripts, 1917-65, undated (Box 10, Folder 110)
      - "Labor and Social Work": printed source materials, 1943-46, undated (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Unpublished Works
    - "Informal Autobiography": typescript, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 112)
    - Annual verses by Bertha C. Reynolds: scrapbook compiled by Reynolds and Rachel A. Levine containing printed texts with notes by Reynolds, 1935-73 (Box 10, Folder 113)
    - Annual verses by Bertha C. Reynolds: printed texts, 1933-73 (Box 10, Folder 114)
    - Religious subjects, 1961-67, undated (Box 10, Folder 115)
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1928, 1947-74 (Box 10, Folder 116)
    - Miscellaneous writings, undated (Box 10, Folder 117)
- Series IV. SUBJECT FILES 1922-1979
  - Organizations
    - American Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born, 1957-75 (Box 11, Folder 118)
    - American Institute for Marxist Studies, 1967-75, undated (Box 11, Folder 119)
    - Avon Institute, 1954, undated (Box 11, Folder 120)
    - Citizens Committee for Constitutional Liberties, 1968-71 (Box 11, Folder 121)
    - The Claude Williams Committee, 1966-79 (Box 11, Folder 122)
    - Communist party, 1969-76 (Box 11, Folder 123)
    - Gould Farm, 1956-75 (Box 11, Folder 124)
    - Methodist Federation for Social Action, 1937, 1967-76 (Box 11, Folder 125)
    - National Association of Social Workers, 1963-79, undated (Box 11, Folder 126)
    - National Conference of Social Work, 1945-46 (Box 11, Folder 127)
    - National Conference on Social Welfare, 1968-79 (Box 11, Folder 128)
    - Packard Manse, 1965-75 (Box 11, Folder 129)
    - Progressive Citizens of America, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 130)
    - Radical Alliance of Social Service Workers, 1974-75 (Box 11, Folder 131)
    - Rosenberg, Ethel and Julius, and Morton Sobell, 1952-68 (Box 11, Folder 132)
    - Southern Conference Educational Fund, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 133)
    - Unions, Personal Service Departments, 1947-51, 1968, undated (Box 11, Folder 134)
    - United Texas Service Committees, 1954-58 (Box 11, Folder 135)
    - Veterans of the Lincoln Brigade, 1964-69 (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Africa, Korea, India, 1948-70, undated (Box 12, Folder 137)
    - China, Cuba, Russia, 1954-71 (Box 12, Folder 138)
    - Civil liberties, 1941-69 (Box 12, Folder 139)
    - Environmental issues, 1942, 1973-77 undated (Box 12, Folder 140)
    - Housing, 1964, undated (Box 12, Folder 141)
    - Luscomb, Florence, 1956-71 (Box 12, Folder 142)
    - "Memoir of a Holocaust Survivor", 1945 (Box 12, Folder 143)
    - Minorities, 1947, 1963, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 144)
    - Peace, 1959, 1975, undated (Box 12, Folder 145)
    - Religion, 1942, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 146)
    - Vietnam, 1968, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 147)
    - Vocabulary building, 1965, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 148)
    - Welfare issues, 1947-69, undated (Box 12, Folder 149)
    - Williams, Frankwood E., 1929, 1936, undated (Box 12, Folder 150)
    - Women, 1935, 1950-73, undated (Box 12, Folder 151)
- Series V. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, PHOTOGRAPHS, AND MEMORABILIA 1907-1979
  - Biographical Material
    - Articles about Bertha C. Reynolds, 1964, 1971-77 (Box 13, Folder 152)
    - Biographical dictionaries: completed formform letters, 1970, 1975-76 (Box 13, Folder 153)
    - Obituaries: articles, clippings, correspondence, 1978 Oct-1979 Jan (Box 13, Folder 154)
    - "Diary," compiled by Bertha C. Reynolds,from family letters, 1894-1924, post-1946 (Box 13, Folder 155)
    - "Diary," compiled by Bertha C. Reynolds from family letters, 1925-1935, post-1946 (Box 13, Folder 156)
    - "Diary," compiled by Bertha C. Reynolds from family letters, 1936-1946, post-1946 (Box 13, Folder 157)
    - Smith College
      - Undergraduate papers, 1907, undated (Box 13, Folder 158)
      - Class of 1908: correspondence, notes, transcript, 1923, 1933,1965-73 (Box 13, Folder 159)
      - Training School for Psychiatric Social Work: memorabilia, reprints, 1918-19 (Box 13, Folder 160)
      - School for Social Work, Alumnae Association: correspondence and form letters, 1943, 1959-75 (Box 13, Folder 161)
      - School for Social Work, Alumni Study Questionnaire: completed form, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 162)
      - School for Social Work: notes and printed material, 196?, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 163)
    - Stoughton
      - Fair Housing and Human Rights Association
        - Correspondence, 1964, 1971-72, undated (Box 13, Folder 164)
        - Notes and printed materials for history course, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 165)
        - Newsletter, 1955-66 (Box 13, Folder 166)
        - Questionnaire, printed material, 1963-70, undated (Box 13, Folder 167)
      - Clippings and printed materials, 1963-73 (Box 13, Folder 168)
      - Historical Society, 1969-77, undated (Box 13, Folder 169)
      - Methodist Church
        - Correspondence and writings by Bertha C. Reynolds, 1961-70 (Box 13, Folder 170)
        - "FISH" and other church activities: printed materials, clippings, 1955-72, undated (Box 13, Folder 171)
    - Personal Papers and Documents
      - Contributions and subscriptions: receipts, 1957, 1968-75, undated (Box 14, Folder 172)
      - Financial notes, 1963-77, undated (Box 14, Folder 173)
      - Frank W. Reynolds: miscellaneous papers, 1972-73, undated (Box 14, Folder 174)
      - Library of Bertha C. Reynolds: lists of books, professional papers, reprints, and journals received with the papers of Bertha C. Reynolds, undated (Box 14, Folder 175)
      - Memberships in organizations: certificates, letters, 1951-66, undated (Box 14, Folder 176)
      - Poems by various authors collected by Bertha C. Reynolds, undated (Box 14, Folder 177)
      - Political and community activities: form letter, notes by Bertha C. Reynolds, printed materials, 1948-49 (Box 14, Folder 178)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1948-77, undated (Box 14, Folder 179)
    - Honors and Tributes
      - Smith College School for Social Work: correspondence, clippings, 1962, 1964, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 180)
      - Smith College School for Social Work, Fiftieth Anniversary: correspondence, citation, printed material, 1967-69 (Box 14, Folder 181)
      - Boston University: correspondence, citation, printed material, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 182)
      - Other honors: citations, speeches about Bertha C. Reynolds, printed material, 1947, 1969-79 (Box 14, Folder 183)
  - Photographs
    - Bertha C. Reynolds, 1938-76 undated (Box 14, Folder 184)
    - Friends, others, miscellaneous, 1925, 1967, 1972-79 (Box 14, Folder 185)
  - Memorabilia
    - Professional papers by friends and colleagues, 1940-77, undated (Box 14, Folder 186)
    - "Sunday in the Park, 1726-1976": plaque, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 187)
    - Books inscribed to Bertha C. Reynolds, 1938-74 (Box 15, Folder 188)
    - Through the Years to Seventy, by Frank W. Reynolds (copyright by Frank W. Reynolds), 1957 (Box 16, Folder 189)
  - Freedom of Information Act documents, 1943-56 (Box 17)
- BOOKS ON SHELF
  - Reynolds, Bertha C., An Uncharted Journey: Fifty Years of Growth in Social Work 1963
  - Southard, E.E. and Mary C. Jarrett, The Kingdom of Evil 1922
- MICROFORMS
  - Microfilm: "Bertha Reynolds - Gentle Radical," by Joan Barnert Goldstein. PhD dissertation, Yeshiva University, 1981 (Box M48)
    [see also Additions to Collection - Acc# 06-60]
- ORAL HISTORIES
  - Oral histories of Bertha C. Reynolds
    - Interview by Phyllis Lowinger, Stoughton, Massachusetts, 1 Dec 1973. Transcript with postscript by Reynolds, 11 pp. (Box 18)
    - Interview by Vida S. Grayson, Stoughton, Massachusetts, 23 Jan 1976. Transcript, 42 pp.; 3 audio cassettes. (Box 18)
    - Interview by Jack Kamaiko, Stoughton, Massachusetts, 6 March 1976. Audio cassette. (Box 18)
    - Interview by Joan L. Goldstein, Stoughton and Brockton, Massachusetts, 5 Dec 1975 - 5 Feb 1977. 5 audio cassettes; transcripts (for 12/5/75 and 2/5/77 only). (Box 18)
  - Oral histories about Bertha C. Reynolds
    - Interview by Joan L. Goldstein with Rachel A. Levine, New York, New York, 16 March 1977. Transcript, 40 pp. (Box 18)
    - Interview by Dorothy Green with Eleanor Flexner, 22 Feb 1988. Transcript, 40 pp. (Box 18)
- ADDITIONS TO COLLECTION
  - Writings by Bertha C. Reynolds and others
    - Bertha C. Reynolds, "Where Do You Get Your Ethics?" undated (Box 19)
    - Bertha C. Reynolds, "Discussion of Psychoanalysis: Ideological Instrument of Imperialism," undated (Box 19)
    - William Schwartz, "Bertha Reynolds as Educator," Catalyst, 1981 (Box 19)
    - Louise Bandler, "Bertha Capen Reynolds: Social Worker of All Times," 1979 (Box 19)
  - Slides
    - 91st birthday (Box 19)
    - Bertha Capen Reynolds centennial (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous writings (pamphlets, articles, reprints) by Bertha C. Reynolds and others (Box 20)
  - Class of 1908 Smith College yearbook (Box 20)
  - Accession #06S-60 (received Aug 2006) (Box 21)
    - Photographs of Reynolds (copies), 1976, undated (Box 21)
    - Correspondence, 1948-62 (Box 21)
    - Tributes and other writings about Reynolds, 1969-75, undated (Box 21)
    - Biographical and autobiographical information, 1938-64, undated (Box 21)
    - Interview with Reynolds: audiocassette, 1975 (Box 21)
    - Speeches, and published writings, 1937-61 (Box 21)
    - Unpublished essays: "Where Do You Get Your Ethics?" (work in progress at the time of BCR's death; might have become a book), 1964 (Box 21)
    - Goldstein, Joan Love
      - Correspondence re: donation of BCR writings to Institute for Marxist Studies, and to Wurtzweiler School of Social Work, 1982, 1994 (Box 21)
      - Writings
        - BCR's essays about the relationship between Marxism and religion, 1984? (Box 21)
        - Copyright registration for dissertation, "Bertha C. Reynolds: Gentle Radical," 1982, [see also Microfilm (M48)] (Box 21)
    - "Socialism and Religion": article or book chapter by Archibald Robinson, undated (Box 21)